http://www.meningitis.org/privacy-policy

Privacy policy
We have developed this policy so that you may feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal information.
Countries in the European Economic Area (EEA) are required to have a similar standard of protection of personal data. This is not always the case outside that area. We do sometimes transfer data outside the EEA and before doing so take steps to ensure that there is adequate protection, as required by relevant Data Protection legislation.
Use of Personal Information
You may need to register to access our website and where you do not register personal information about you will not be collected by us.
If you register for our services, any details you provide may be stored for use on future visits, as we do not want you to give us any information more than once. The details you give us may be combined with information about your use of the Meningitis Research Foundation website(s) and information from other of our records in order to provide you with online services you request.
Email addresses
We respect the privacy of personal email accounts and we store your email addresses just as securely as other personal information. We will not send you unwanted email messages or junk mail, and your details will not be passed to any organisation outside the Group for marketing purposes without your explicit permission.
However, we may use email in response to enquiries you make about our services or service issues.
Disclosure of information
We take all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorised access to your personal data.
We sometimes use other companies to provide some of our services or to provide services to us. To enable them to do this, we may need to let them process your personal information. Our staff and those working for our agents or contractors have a responsibility to keep your information confidential and are only allowed to use it to offer products and services on our behalf.
Right of access to your information
If you want to know exactly what personal information Meningitis Research Foundation holds on you, you can obtain it. If it transpires that the information held is inaccurate, we will make the necessary amendments and confirm to you that these have been made. Please write to the Data Protection Officer at the Meningitis Research Foundation.
How we protect your data
Our general Email enquiry forms are not sent via an encrypted channel and for this reason we ask that you do not include confidential information when using them (such as bank account details).
Messages sent and received via the message service when you are logged into your accounts via our internet banking service are encrypted and therefore secure.
Use of Cookies
Cookies – Your website may work with third parties to research certain usage and activities on our website on our behalf. No personal information about you is shared, however in the course of conducting this research these third parties may place a unique "cookie" on your browser.
A cookie is a small file which is sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard disc and helps Your website understand and track your use of the site and where it can improve the information and services provided. Your website uses cookies solely to gather information on IP addresses, to analyse trends, administer the site, track user's movements on the site and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to other personally identifiable information and will not be used to deliver targeted marketing messages. For information about blocking the use of cookies, please refer to the instructions/help screen on your Internet browser. Please note that you may not be able to use or access certain parts of the site or online services if you block the use of cookies.
Changes - As a result of improvements we make to our services, amendments to laws or regulation or developments in the technology or processes we use, we may change the information we hold about you and/or the way in which or the purposes for which we process such information. Where we require your consent to such change we will notify you of the change. However, unless you inform us otherwise, we will deem your continued use of products and services to which the change relates to constitute your consent to the relevant change.
Live Chat
We use live chat software on our website, this is provided by Click4Assistance, a 3rd party UK based Software Company. Information regarding how the data is processed and stored can be viewed here.
Please help us
We wish our service to meet your expectations on all occasions. To do so we need the information we hold about you to be accurate and up to date. Please help us by informing us promptly of any changes to your personal circumstances.
This Privacy Policy supplements, but does not supersede, any data protection notice that has previously been provided to you.
If you have a query or complaint regarding our privacy policy do email us
Share this
Buy hope for families
90p/€1 produces a detailed ‘Your Guide’ information pack for parents when a child is recovering from meningitis
Donate now
Helpline
The MRF Membership and Support team are here for you for any questions you might have about meningitis and septicaemia and their effects on you or your family and friends.
MRF’s helpline hours are Monday – Friday 9am – 5pmTel: UK 080 8800 3344/Ireland 1800 41 33 44
Email
Research programme
We fund research into the prevention, detection and treatment of meningitis and sepsis
Our current projects
Defeating meningitis by 2030
A global vision for meningitis by 2030 and an action plan to get there.
Find out more
Carol Currie
Director of Finance and Administration
If you'd like to know anything more about this aspect of MRF's work, do get in touch
Tel: 0333 405 6273
carolc@meningitis.org
Email Me
